Hi, my name is Chell Garcia-Trias, and I'm a modern dancer in Austin Texas.
I'm going to show you how to do downward dog, which is a yoga position.
However, I do it the way I learned it in modern dance, which is a little bit different.
So, basically I'm going to come to all fours, as if I was in a dog position.
But then I'm going to push my knees off of the ground, and I'm going to push my hips up towards the ceiling.
As much as possible I want to have a tight little angle there, a flat back, and straight legs.
And I want to push my ankles towards the ground, my heels towards the ground.
So, I'm going to put my hands down on the ground, tuck my toes under, and push my hips towards the ceiling.
While I'm in this position, I'm going to drop my shoulders, I do not want my shoulders up by my ears, I want to drop them into my back, drop my shoulder blades into my back.
Push through my hands, push through my feet, drop my heels towards the ground, straighten my knees.
There's a lot of things to think about here.
And everybody is going to be in a different place with it.
You might feel you can't bring your heels to the ground, that's fine.
You might find you're not ready to straighten your legs, bend your knees a little bit, that's fine.
Really, push through all of the fingers through your hands and the palms of your hands.
It's really important, whatever position you're in here, that you're pushing through your shoulder blades, pushing them into the ground, dropping your shoulders, pushing your arms, reaching with your hips.
Take deep breaths while you're there, so that you're relaxing and releasing, and deepening the stretch.
You'll feel a nice intense stretch all the way into your calves in that position.
So that is a great way to do downward dog when you're in modern dance.